<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Hackathon on /home/fel1x</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/109/tags/hackathon/</link><description>Recent content in Hackathon on /home/fel1x</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</managingEditor><webMaster>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</webMaster><copyright>© 2025 Felix Hoang</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/109/tags/hackathon/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My STEAM Hacks 2023 experience</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/109/posts/hackathon-steam-hacks-2023/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</author><guid>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/109/posts/hackathon-steam-hacks-2023/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I want to share my experience with you about the project I worked on during the Steam Hacks 2023 competition. Although my team did not win any major awards for this project, it was an incredible learning opportunity for me, particularly in terms of coding. Moreover, I also gained valuable insights into the collaborative process through working with my amazing new friend from Son La - Minh Chau.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>TechBurst – Revolutionary AI Solution for Identifying Counterfeit Products</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/109/projects/steam-hacks-2023-techburst-counterfeit/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</author><guid>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/109/projects/steam-hacks-2023-techburst-counterfeit/</guid><description>This project aims to provide users with a reliable solution to identify counterfeit products. Originally designed as a C2C Ecommerce Platform, the project has evolved to focus solely on counterfeit detection. The system offers two methods for users to verify product authenticity: utilizing a Teachable Machine model and employing a barcode scanner.</description></item><item><title>Reware App – Ewaste Management Solutions</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/109/projects/sft2022-reware-app/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</author><guid>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/109/projects/sft2022-reware-app/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is my product created while participating in Samsung Solve for Tomorrow 2022, a STEM contest organized by Samsung Electronic Company that encourages problem-solving skills and showcases the positive impact of young minds on society, with over 76,000 participants nationwide&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Green Express – Initial Business Concept of Fostering Ewaste Reduction</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/109/projects/basf-green-express/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</author><guid>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/109/projects/basf-green-express/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This product emerged from my participation in the BASF Innovation Challenge, a national competition that empowers students to devise sustainability solutions, where we secured the 3rd Runner Up prize. While our aim was not the highest award, this competition established a robust foundation for me and our team to persist in researching and developing solutions to address the serious issue of e-waste&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>