<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Self-Hosted on /home/fel1x</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/tags/self-hosted/</link><description>Recent content in Self-Hosted on /home/fel1x</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</managingEditor><webMaster>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</webMaster><copyright>© 2025 Felix Hoang</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/tags/self-hosted/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On-Premise 101 (part 1): Building a 3-Node Proxmox Cluster</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/on-premise-hardware/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</author><guid>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/on-premise-hardware/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;You might have heard about the recent AWS outage that caused many services to go down. To think that half of the internet relies on a single service is crazy, even if it might be the best in its field. The engineers at AWS have done many things to prevent this, such as high availability, multi-region, zones, etc., but if a critical part of it still goes down, the whole thing goes down too. Therefore, if you don&amp;rsquo;t want to give all your money and trust to a single company, you might want to explore the on-premise option, which is self-hosting.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building a Secure Network for Homelab with OpenWRT, NextDNS, Tailscale, and a VPS</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/self-hosted-network-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</author><guid>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/self-hosted-network-design/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A long time ago, my house only had 1 router, located on the third floor. So whenever we needed to access the internet while having dinner on the first floor, we needed to enable 4G or walk near the stairs just to receive a fraction of the WiFi signal. My father decided to give me an important task, which was to figure out how to solve this issue. I initially bought a simple WiFi extender located on the second floor, but after using it for a month, even though we could receive a strong signal from it, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t access the internet because the signal from the router on the 3rd floor to the WiFi extender on the 2nd floor was still really weak.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Accessing a Homelab from a Locked-Down PC with a Travel Router</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/self-hosted-travel-router/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</author><guid>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/self-hosted-travel-router/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A week ago, my laptop died. When I booted it up, it said something like, &lt;code&gt;fTPM is corrupted, press Y to reset or N to do nothing&lt;/code&gt;. Neither of them helped me boot into my machine. So I had a severe mental attack back then, because that machine was the primary one that helped me do my work for school, my lab, and my personal projects. I was lucky to have my friend lend me an old laptop of his, but it was pretty bulky, so I figured I couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring it to school. Therefore, I had to go to the school library to do my work on its public computers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Migrating and Rebuilding My RKE2 Kubernetes Cluster on Proxmox</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/terraform-ansible-proxmox-k8s-2/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</author><guid>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/terraform-ansible-proxmox-k8s-2/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the past few days, I tried deploying an RKE2 Kubernetes cluster on my home Proxmox setup. My initial setup worked, but it quickly became apparent that things weren’t stable or sustainable. RKE2’s auto-deployment behavior, the embedded etcd database, and service load balancing all caused performance and manageability issues. It wasn’t “buggy” in the literal sense, but definitely felt rigid and inefficient — not something I would consider a best-practice deployment for a long-term homelab setup.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How I Struggled (and Learned) to Deploy a Kubernetes Cluster on Proxmox with Terraform and Ansible</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/terraform-ansible-proxmox-k8s/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</author><guid>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/terraform-ansible-proxmox-k8s/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Hi everyone! Have you ever tried using AWS, GCP, or Azure? It’s an amazing experience, right? The ability to spin up a couple of VMs, a Kubernetes (K8s) cluster, set up load balancers, high availability — all in just a few clicks. You can focus entirely on developing your product. I mean, yeah, why bother with the hassle of learning how all of that works under the hood?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Automating Manga Translations: My Journey to a Seamless Reading Experience</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/self-hosted-manga-trans/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</author><guid>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/self-hosted-manga-trans/</guid><description>&lt;h2 class="relative group"&gt;Video demo:
&lt;div id="video-demo" class="anchor"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span
class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 -start-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100 select-none"&gt;
&lt;a class="text-primary-300 dark:text-neutral-700 !no-underline" href="#video-demo" aria-label="Anchor"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;lite-youtube videoid="RgkC246Ul44" playlabel="RgkC246Ul44" params=""&gt;&lt;/lite-youtube&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2 class="relative group"&gt;The Struggle: Why I Needed This
&lt;div id="the-struggle-why-i-needed-this" class="anchor"&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;span
class="absolute top-0 w-6 transition-opacity opacity-0 -start-6 not-prose group-hover:opacity-100 select-none"&gt;
&lt;a class="text-primary-300 dark:text-neutral-700 !no-underline" href="#the-struggle-why-i-needed-this" aria-label="Anchor"&gt;#&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Have you ever stumbled upon a manga so niche and obscure that it never gets an official English release? That was me—desperately trying to read intimate and underrated series that weren’t even on MangaDex, likely due to copyright issues.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My First Server Was Office Trash: A Self-Hosting Story</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/self-hosted-initial-story/</link><pubDate>Sun, 27 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</author><guid>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/self-hosted-initial-story/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;It all started with a computer my mom saved from the trash heap at her office. It was a standard HP Prodesk 600 G4—nothing special, and since I already had a PC and a laptop, I had no idea what to do with it. Just installing Windows on it felt like a waste. I knew it could be something more than just another desktop collecting dust.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>