<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Openwrt on /home/fel1x</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/tags/openwrt/</link><description>Recent content in Openwrt on /home/fel1x</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><managingEditor>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</managingEditor><webMaster>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</webMaster><copyright>© 2025 Felix Hoang</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/tags/openwrt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Building a Secure Network for Homelab with OpenWRT, NextDNS, Tailscale, and a VPS</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/self-hosted-network-design/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</author><guid>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/self-hosted-network-design/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A long time ago, my house only had 1 router, located on the third floor. So whenever we needed to access the internet while having dinner on the first floor, we needed to enable 4G or walk near the stairs just to receive a fraction of the WiFi signal. My father decided to give me an important task, which was to figure out how to solve this issue. I initially bought a simple WiFi extender located on the second floor, but after using it for a month, even though we could receive a strong signal from it, we couldn&amp;rsquo;t access the internet because the signal from the router on the 3rd floor to the WiFi extender on the 2nd floor was still really weak.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Accessing a Homelab from a Locked-Down PC with a Travel Router</title><link>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/self-hosted-travel-router/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><author>xuanphuc.a1gv@gmail.com (Felix Hoang)</author><guid>https://phuchoang2603.github.io/previews/96/posts/self-hosted-travel-router/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;A week ago, my laptop died. When I booted it up, it said something like, &lt;code&gt;fTPM is corrupted, press Y to reset or N to do nothing&lt;/code&gt;. Neither of them helped me boot into my machine. So I had a severe mental attack back then, because that machine was the primary one that helped me do my work for school, my lab, and my personal projects. I was lucky to have my friend lend me an old laptop of his, but it was pretty bulky, so I figured I couldn&amp;rsquo;t bring it to school. Therefore, I had to go to the school library to do my work on its public computers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>